The term “environmentalist” can mean different things.
“环保主义者”这个词可以有不同的含义。
It used to refer to people trying to protect wildlife and natural ecosystems.
这个词过去指的是努力保护野生动植物和自然生态系统的人。
In the 21st century, the term has evolved to capture the need to combat human-made climate change.
到了21世纪，这个词的含义已经演变，涵盖了应对人为气候变化的需要。
The distinction between these two strands of environmentalism is the cause of a split within the scientific community about nuclear energy.
环保主义这两个分支之间的区别，是科学界内部在核能问题上产生分歧的原因。
On one side are purists who believe nuclear power isn’t worth the risk and the exclusive solution to the climate crisis is renewable energy.
一方是纯粹主义者，他们认为核能不值得冒这个风险，解决气候危机的唯一办法是可再生能源。
The opposing side agrees that renewables are crucial, but says society needs an amount of power available to meet consumers’ basic demands when the sun isn’t shining and the wind isn’t blowing.
对立的一方认同可再生能源至关重要，但又表示，社会需要一定量的可用电力，以便在没有阳光、也没有风的时候满足消费者的基本需求。
Nuclear energy, being far cleaner than oil, gas and coal, is a natural option, especially where hydroelectric capacity is limited.
核能比石油、天然气和煤炭清洁得多，是一个自然而然的选择，在水力发电能力有限的地方尤其如此。
Leon Clarke, who helped author reports for the UN’s Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change, isn’t an uncritical supporter of nuclear energy, but says it’s a valuable option to have if we’re serious about reaching carbon neutrality.
利昂·克拉克曾参与为联合国政府间气候变化专门委员会撰写报告，他并不盲目支持核能，但他表示，如果我们真心想实现碳中和，保留核能这一选项很有价值。
“Core to all of this is the degree to which you think we can actually meet climate goals with 100% renewables,” he said.
他说：“这一切的核心在于，你认为我们在多大程度上真能依靠100%可再生能源实现气候目标。”
“If you don’t believe we can do it, and you care about the climate, you are forced to think about something like nuclear.”
“如果你不相信我们能做到这一点，同时又关心气候，那就不得不考虑核能之类的选项。”
The achievability of universal 100% renewability is similarly contentious.
普遍实现100%可再生能源是否可行，同样存在争议。
Cities such as Burlington, Vermont, have been “100% renewable” for years.
多年来，佛蒙特州伯灵顿等城市的能源一直是“100%可再生”的。
But these cities often have small populations, occasionally still rely on fossil fuel energy and have significant renewable resources at their immediate disposal.
但这些城市往往人口不多，偶尔仍要依靠化石燃料能源，而且手边就有大量可再生资源可供利用。
Meanwhile, countries that manage to run off renewables typically do so thanks to extraordinary hydroelectric capabilities.
与此同时，成功依靠可再生能源运转的国家，通常是凭借超乎寻常的水力发电能力才做到这一点。
Germany stands as the best case study for a large, industrialized country pushing into green energy.
德国堪称大型工业化国家大力转向绿色能源的最佳研究案例。
Chancellor Angela Merkel in 2011 announced Energiewende, an energy transition that would phase out nuclear and coal while phasing in renewables.
2011年，安格拉·默克尔总理宣布实施“能源转型”（Energiewende），计划逐步淘汰核能和煤炭，同时逐步引入可再生能源。
Wind and solar power generation has increased over 400% since 2010, and renewables provided 46% of the country’s electricity in 2019.
自2010年以来，风能和太阳能发电量增长了400%以上，2019年，可再生能源提供了该国46%的电力。
But progress has halted in recent years.
但近年来，进展陷入了停滞。
The instability of renewables doesn’t just mean energy is often not produced at night, but also that solar and wind can overwhelm the grid during the day, forcing utilities to pay customers to use their electricity.
可再生能源的不稳定性不仅意味着夜间往往没有能源产出，还意味着白天太阳能和风能可能让电网不堪重负，迫使公用事业公司花钱请客户用自家的电。
Lagging grid infrastructure struggles to transport this overabundance of green energy from Germany’s north to its industrial south, meaning many factories still run on coal and gas.
滞后的电网基础设施难以把这些过剩的绿色能源从德国北部输送到工业集中的南部，这意味着许多工厂仍然靠煤炭和天然气运转。
The political limit has also been reached in some places, with citizens meeting the construction of new wind turbines with loud protests.
一些地方也已触及政治上的极限：民众对新建风力涡轮机报以强烈抗议。
The result is that Germany’s greenhouse gas emissions have fallen by around 11.5% since 2010—slower than the EU average of 13.5%.
结果是，自2010年以来，德国的温室气体排放量下降了约11.5%，下降速度慢于欧盟平均水平（13.5%）。